# **Taylor Guenthner**

wtguenthner@gmail.com | 770-337-7073 | Decatur, GA LinkedIn: taylor-guenthner | GitHub: wtguenthner | Portfolio: https://wtguenthner.github.io/react-portfolio

## **Summary**

Strong leader and decision maker with the ability to communicate with a wide range of personalities on a personal and professional level. Began a career in hospitality with experience collaborating with others and adapting in difficult situations. Determined and self-motivated to make a career change in software development.

### **Technical Skills**

Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS, Node.js

Database Management: MySQL, MongoDB, GraphQL

Libraries / Framework: jQuery, React, Express, Sequelize

#### **Education**

**Georgia State University** 

Attended 2008-2013 Computer Science

**Georgia Tech Full Stack Web Development** 

04/2022-10/2022 MERN Stack Certification

# **Projects**

**Event Finder** | **Github:** https://github.com/wtguenthner/Event\_Finder | **Deployed:** https://mmmphoto.github.io/Event-Finder

- Search for events by your location or city.
- Uses API calls to fetch data based on the user's input and displays accordingly.
- HTML, CSS, Javascript, APIs,

**Dungeons & Devs | Github:** https://github.com/wtguenthner/Dungeons-Devs | **Deployed:** https://dungeons-devs.herokuapp.com

 Interactive card game with multiple classes to choose from and stat cards to boost your character.

- Interacts with the server created by express to create and store the user's profile via a MySQL database.
- Express, Sequelize, MySQL

**Dungeons & Devs with React | Github:** https://github.com/hackpres/DnDevs\_React | **Deployed:** https://dungeons-n-devs.herokuapp.com

- Interactive card game. Battle through three "bosses" using randomly generated cards.
- React application that uses MongoDB to create and store the user's profile.
- React, MongoDB, Apollo, Nodejs

# **Experience**

## Operations Manager Longleaf Restaurant

2018 - 2022

Atlanta, GA

Managed the front of the house operations and was directly involved in guest relationships throughout the day. Lead a team of 25+ employees to successfully execute the daily functions of the restaurant.

- Implemented policies and procedures to increase efficiency
- Hired & trained all new employees
- Organized and maintained alcohol orders to decrease cost and waste

Shift Supervisor

#### **ROOM** @ Twelve Hotel & Restaurant

2017 - 2018 Atlanta, GA

Maintained daily operations with a focus on hospitality in an upscale and fast paced dining environment. Monitored labor and food costs to ensure maximum profit margins.

- Expedited food ensuring quality plate presentation
- Emphasis on guest relationships
- Organized and executed banquet events